<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-04-04T03:15:56+00:00</updated><id>https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">How to use Psychographics to improve your product</title><link href="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2022/how-to-use-psychographics-to-improve-your-product/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to use Psychographics to improve your product"/><published>2022-06-22T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-22T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2022/how-to-use-psychographics-to-improve-your-product</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2022/how-to-use-psychographics-to-improve-your-product/"><![CDATA[<p>Misunderstanding target user is the number one reason for product failure. To avoid this you should understand your audience really well.</p> <p>Psychographics helps you understand your users based on their aspirations, interests and attitudes.</p> <h2 id="what-is-psychographics"><strong>What is psychographics?</strong></h2> <p>Psychographics is a methodology of studying users based on their attitudes, interests, aspirations, values and opinions.</p> <p>Demographic segmentation helps you explain customer information like age, gender, income and location. But this will not give you any insights into what motivates your users to use your product. To understand the cognitive factors involved in your customer decisions you need psychographics. Demographics help us understand <strong>who</strong> uses our product and psychographics tells us <strong>why</strong>.</p> <p>Psychographics also can be used to represent what we call “<strong>culture</strong>” around a product or service.</p> <p><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20230529095141im_/https://hk587c.n3cdn1.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Demographic-1024x576.png" alt="Demographics vs psychographics"/></p> <p>Demographics vs psychographics</p> <h2 id="how-to-understand-your-users-using-psychographics"><strong>How to understand your users using psychographics?</strong></h2> <p>To identify motivations and emotions of your users Psychographics use <strong>AIO variables</strong> – activities, interests and opinions.</p> <p><strong>Activities :</strong> Activities indicate what your users do, what they buy and how they spend their time. Eg. Work, hobbies, Social Events, vacation, entertainment, shopping, sports.</p> <p><strong>Interests :</strong> Interest focus on what the consumer preference and priorities are. Eg. family, recreation, fashion, media.</p> <p><strong>Opinion</strong> : Opinion deals with users views and feelings on world, local, economic and social affairs.</p> <p>Here is a list of psychographic factors you can use to segment your customers with.</p> <ul> <li>Goals</li> <li>Values</li> <li>Dreams</li> <li>Hobbies</li> <li>Daily activities</li> <li>Favorite social media</li> <li>Beliefs</li> <li>Challenges</li> <li>Fears</li> <li>Lifestyle choices</li> </ul> <h2 id="how-to-collect-psychographic-data"><strong>How to collect psychographic data?</strong></h2> <p>It is easier to get demographic or transaction data of your users. You can easily find demographic information in Google analytics and address, name etc. in transaction details. But it is challenging to collect psychographic data from product perspective. Here are few places that you can look for psychographic data.</p> <h4 id="1-product-feedback-surveys"><strong>1. Product Feedback surveys</strong></h4> <p>Quantitative data tells you what, where and how much and qualitative tells you ‘why’. The real trick to success here is to ask the right questions. Also make sure when you are asking for feedback you place it at the right position of your user journey. After giving your user something of value through the use of your product, is the ideal time to ask for feedback.</p> <h4 id="2-customer-tickets"><strong>2. Customer tickets</strong></h4> <p>You can gather psychographic information by looking at customer service tickets or product reviews.</p> <h4 id="3-product-analytics"><strong>3. Product Analytics</strong></h4> <p>You can use a psychographic lens to analyse the analytics data you currently have and gain some insights. Use below questions to analyse your user data</p> <ul> <li>Look at what moved people to click or buy in the past?</li> <li>On which content do they spend the most time?</li> <li>Which calls-to-action convert better than others?</li> <li>Where does the majority of your website traffic come from?</li> <li>Where do people go after leaving your site?</li> </ul> <h4 id="4-market-research-companies"><strong>4. Market research companies</strong></h4> <p>There are market research companies that collect psychographics data for different verticals. Companies that have already conducted research in your chosen vertical might provide you with the data you need.</p> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>Deep understanding of your user is the key to a successful product. Psychographics helps you build that understanding and you can build a product you know your users will love.</p> <p>Have you done any psychographic research yet? What was your experience?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Product"/><category term="Management"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Misunderstanding target user is the number one reason for product failure. To avoid this you should understand your audience really well.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creative Selection: Inside Apple’s Design Process During the Golden Age of Steve Jobs Book Review</title><link href="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2021/creative-selection-inside-apples-design-process-during-the-golden-age-of-steve-jobs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creative Selection: Inside Apple’s Design Process During the Golden Age of Steve Jobs Book Review"/><published>2021-07-31T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-31T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2021/creative-selection-inside-apples-design-process-during-the-golden-age-of-steve-jobs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2021/creative-selection-inside-apples-design-process-during-the-golden-age-of-steve-jobs/"><![CDATA[<p>The iPad Keyboard I am using to type this review is a central character of the book Creative</p> <p>The iPad Keyboard I am using to type this review is a central character of the book Creative Selection. That is an interesting coincidence isn’t it? </p> <p>Creative Selection is about Ken Kocienda’s look at Apple’s creative process. He spent 15 years at Apple working on various products like Safari, iPhone and iPad Keyboards. He explains the creative process behind all these products in detail. I liked the detailed explanation of things and his narration style but at times it tends to be a bit dramatic. </p> <p>Apple’s focus on demo’s and how it plays a big role internally and externally is interesting. His take on development vs seeing the larger picture is right. Programmers usually pay attention to the parts that didn’t work quite right yet like fixing bugs and pushing for the next improvement. It is quite difficult to maintain a wider perspective in the midst of making. </p> <p>Story of the iPhone and iPad keyboard is the best part of this book. Once you finish reading it you can’t look at this keyboard the same way again. You will definitely see why Apple say that they always try to be at the intersection of technology and liberal arts.</p> <p>Overall this is a really good read if you are curious about understanding how products are made in apple. My only complaint is about the over dramatisation of events.</p> <p>Here is a section of the book talking about how Apple looks at creative decisions.</p> <blockquote> <p>“it’s crucial to make the right call about whether to use an algorithm or a heuristic in a specific situation. This is why the Google experiment with forty-one shades of blue seems so foreign to me, accustomed as I am to the Apple approach. Google used an A/B test to make a color choice. It used a single predetermined value criterion and defined it like so: The best shade of blue is the one that people clicked most often in the test. This is an algorithm.</p> <p>At Apple, we never considered the notion of an algorithmically correct color. We used demos to pick colors and animation timings, and we put our faith in our sense of taste. When we went looking for the right “finger movement in accordance with a rule,” as mentioned in the excerpt I included from the ’949 Patent, we made a subjective call. We developed heuristics.</p> <p>At the same time, we weren’t overly touchy-feely about everything. Creating optimized algorithms was a significant part of developing the software for the iPhone, as it was for making Safari before it. What was important was that there remained a tension and flow between the algorithms[…]”</p> <p>Excerpt From: Ken Kocienda. “Creative Selection”</p> </blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Books"/><category term="Books"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The iPad Keyboard I am using to type this review is a central character of the book Creative]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Indistractable: How to Control Your Attention and Choose Your Life Book Review</title><link href="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2021/indistractable-how-to-control-your-attention-and-choose-your-life-book-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Indistractable: How to Control Your Attention and Choose Your Life Book Review"/><published>2021-07-26T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2021/indistractable-how-to-control-your-attention-and-choose-your-life-book-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2021/indistractable-how-to-control-your-attention-and-choose-your-life-book-review/"><![CDATA[<p>“time management is pain management” is the biggest take away of this book. Distractions cost us time, and like all actions, they are spurred by the desire to escape discomfort.</p> <p>Opposite of distraction is not “focus”, opposite of distraction is “traction”. Even though this is a silly word play, it makes sense. Focus doesn’t sound like a progress making word and traction does. </p> <p>This book have a lot of actionable tips neatly arranged in different chapters. Does it really help you understand everything about distractions? I would say not really. You could read only notes in end of each chapter and also get the main ideas. </p> <p>Pick this up if you like a step by step guide for managing distractions. If you are looking for big ideas in this area then stick to first few chapters and read summary of rest of chapters. </p> <h2 id="the-indistractable-model">The Indistractable Model</h2> <table> <tbody> <tr> <td>![Nir Eyal on becoming indistractable in the age of tech</td> <td>productboard](https://web.archive.org/web/20230529074854im_/https://productboard.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/screen-shot-2019-12-16-at-10-07-45-pm.png)</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p><em>Four Step guide to become indistractable</em></p> <p><strong>1. Master Internal Triggers</strong></p> <p>Understand the root cause of distraction. Distraction is about more than your devices. Separate proximate causes from the root cause.</p> <p>• All motivation is a desire to escape discomfort. If a behavior was previously effective at providing relief, we’re likely to continue using it as a tool to escape discomfort.</p> <p>• Anything that stops discomfort is potentially addictive, but that doesn’t make it irresistible. If you know the drivers of your behavior, you can take steps to manage them.</p> <p><strong>2. Make Time for traction</strong></p> <p>You can’t call something a distraction unless you know what it is distracting you from. Planning ahead is the only way to know the difference between traction and distraction.</p> <p><strong>3. Hack Back External Triggers</strong></p> <p>External triggers often lead to distraction. Cues in our environment like the pings, dings, rings from devices as well as interruptions from other people, frequently take us off track</p> <p>We must ask: is this trigger saving me, or am I serving it? Then, we can hack the external triggers that don’t serve us.</p> <p><strong>4. Prevent Distractions with Facts</strong></p> <p>Being indistractable not only requires keeping distraction out. It also necessitates reining ourselves in.</p> <p>Precommitments should only be used after other three indistractable strategies have already been applied.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Books"/><category term="Books"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“time management is pain management” is the biggest take away of this book. Distractions cost us time, and like all actions, they are spurred by the desire to escape discomfort.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On the Shortness of Life – Seneca</title><link href="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2017/on-the-shortness-of-life-seneca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On the Shortness of Life – Seneca"/><published>2017-01-22T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-22T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2017/on-the-shortness-of-life-seneca</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2017/on-the-shortness-of-life-seneca/"><![CDATA[<p>On the shortness of life came across to me as a recommendation from the book <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20230529081952/https://web.archive.org/web/20170922131524/http://amzn.to/2smHYeJ">How to Live on 24 Hours a Day</a>. I wanted to read Seneca for a long time so I decided to start with this one. This is a very small book with 105 pages, but it carries the best content that I read this year.</p> <p>This book is divided into three parts. First one is the essay “On the shortness of life”. Seneca shares his views on how to live a life to the fullest. You cannot expect any sugar coated words from a stoic so you might feel sometimes that the words are hitting you very hard. But towards the end you will realize how relevant his ideas are even today. This is my favorite essay in this book.</p> <p>The second part is Seneca addressing his mother on the occasion of his exile. In “Consolation to Helvia” he refers to his exile as a benefit not a punishment. This is historically an interesting essay, you will understand the attitude of society towards women in that era. For me this essay was not as interesting as the other two because It had many references to other stories and events happened in that era.</p> <p>“On Tranquility of Mind” is Seneca responding to his friend Serenus’s letter. Serenus seeking Seneca’s advice on how to cure him of anxiety, worry and disgust with life. Seneca talks about self-knowledge, ordering priorities, public service and mastering fear in this part.</p> <p>Here is few of my favourite quotes from this book.</p> <blockquote> <p>“You act like mortals in all that you fear, and like immortals in all that you desire.”</p> <p>“The pain of a wound is the same in the largest and the smallest bodies. Plucking out hair hurts bald people just as much as those with hair.”</p> <p>“They loose the day in waiting for the night, and the night in fearing the dawn.”</p> <p>“No man has been shattered by the blows of fortune unless he was first deceived by her favours.”</p> <p>“People are frugal in guarding their personal property; but as soon as it comes to squandering time they are most wasteful of the one thing in which it is right to be stingy.”</p> <p>“And so there is no reason for you to think that any man has lived long because he has grey hairs or wrinkles, he has not lived long – he has existed long. For what if you should think that man had had a long voyage who had been caught by a fierce storm as soon as he left harbour, and, swept hither and thither by a succession of winds that raged from different quarters, had been driven in a circle around the same course? Not much voyaging did he have, but much tossing about.”</p> <p>“The evil of taking our cue from others has become so deeply ingrained that even the most basic feeling, grief, degenerates into imitation”</p> <p>“It’s not that we have a short time to live, but that we waste much of it. Life is long enough, and it’s been given to us in generous measure for accomplishing the greatest things, if the whole of it is well invested.”</p> <p>“What does it matter what ground I stand on.”</p> <p>“I shall never ashamed to go to a bad author for a good quotation.”</p> </blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Books"/><category term="Books"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the shortness of life came across to me as a recommendation from the book How to Live on 24 Hours a Day. I wanted to read Seneca for a long time so I decided to start with this one. This is a very small book with 105 pages, but it carries the best content that I read this year.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sapiens – A brief history of humankind</title><link href="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2017/sapiens-a-brief-history-of-humankind/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sapiens – A brief history of humankind"/><published>2017-01-07T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-07T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2017/sapiens-a-brief-history-of-humankind</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2017/sapiens-a-brief-history-of-humankind/"><![CDATA[<p>Once in a while you will read a book and it will bring a radical shift in your perspective. Sapiens is a book like that. This books tells us how an animal born with no significance grown to become god like. Dr. Yuval Noah Harari did a great job writing the entire human history in just 400 pages. His simple writing style and presentation with illustrations explains each and every concept perspicaciously.</p> <p>This book is divided into four major sections <strong>The Cognitive Revolution, Agricultural Revolution, Unification of Humankind</strong> and <strong>Scientific Revolution</strong><em>.</em> In each of these sections Harari explains how human beings lived in that era and how this lifestyle affected their environment.</p> <p><strong>1. The Cognitive Revolution</strong></p> <p>Cognitive revolution started about 70,000 years ago. Unlike other animals Sapiens have the gift of imagination. No other animal can live in an imagined reality. They live in pure reality where a cow is a cow, but in human society we have different meaning for cow. It is no longer a normal cow it is considered as a mother and in some part of the world we worship it. Imagined reality opened new realms in human behavior. Now if you look around you see most of the things that we use daily like money, religions, companies, bank, nations, organisations are not real objects. You cannot touch and feel these things. They exists only in our collective imagination. We use myths and stories to build this universe of imagined reality.</p> <blockquote> <p>“Telling effective stories is not easy. The difficulty lies not in telling the story, but in convincing everyone else to believe it. Much of history revolves around this question: how does one convince millions of people to believe particular stories about gods, or nations, or limited liability companies? Yet when it succeeds, it gives Sapiens immense power, because it enables millions of strangers to cooperate and work towards common goals.”</p> </blockquote> <p>It is very difficult for one million apes to work together towards a common goal, because they don’t have this web of imagined reality. For them trusting each other takes a lot of time. But for sapiens trusting each other is simple because of imagined reality. If two people believe in one imagined reality there is a higher chance of them trusting each other. And today imagined reality is far more powerful than anything else. We can say that the existence of reality itself is depended on this imagined reality. As Harari put it</p> <blockquote> <p>“As time went by, the imagined reality become ever more powerful, so that today the very survival of rivers, trees and lions depends on the grace of imagined entities such as United nations and Google.”</p> </blockquote> <p>Harari is saying many of our present day social and psychological characters are developed during pre-agricultural era. For example we might have got craving for high calorie food from hunter-gatherer ancestors. At that time when you get some high calorie food the only way to use it was to eat more. There was no guarantee that you will get this again tomorrow.</p> <blockquote> <p>“Today we may be living in high-rise apartments with over stuffed refrigerators, but our DNA still thinks we are in the savannah. That’s what makes us spoon down an entire tub of Ben&amp;Jerry’s when we find one in the freezer and wash it down with a jumbo Coke.”</p> </blockquote> <h3 id="2-the-agricultural-revolution"><strong>2. The Agricultural Revolution</strong></h3> <p>The first chapter of this section is called <strong>History’s Biggest Fraud.</strong> Well, there is a reason behind it.</p> <p>Agricultural revolution started around 10,000 years ago. Sapiens who hunted wild animals and gathered wild plants started sowing seeds, watering plants and domesticated animals. It was a revolution in the way humans lived. We heard many stories about how this revolution fueled the progress of humanity but there is no evidence that this actually made any progress in their life. Sapiens used to have a very good diet, they ate wide variety of food gathered from wilderness, but agriculture restricted it to very few. Also farming took a lot of effort and reduced time for leisure.</p> <blockquote> <p>“The agriculture revolution certainly enlarged the sum total of food at the disposal of humankind, but the extra food does not translated into better diet or more leisure. Rather it translated into population explosions and pampered elites. The average farmer worked harder than the average forager, and got a worse diet in return. The agriculture revolution was history’s biggest fraud.”</p> </blockquote> <p>Harari is saying</p> <blockquote> <p>“We did not domesticate wheat. It domesticated us.”</p> </blockquote> <p>May be this is true. Agriculture could be a trap that our ancestors fallen into and we still haven’t came out of it. But we should also see the other side. Why they fell for this trap in the first place?. Before farming food was the first priority and they spend almost their entire life for gathering food. But after agriculture started sapiens finally got some time to do other business as well. This paved the way for an entire new style of living. It is hard to say that agriculture changed the lives of sapiens for good or bad. If it didn’t happened we would be seeing it in a different perspective.</p> <p>Agriculture solved the availability of food. People settle down around farms and this started bringing hierarchies in their social order.</p> <p>**Imagined Order<br/> **Harari is trying to see the world we live in as a combination of two things, imagination and reality. The reality around us is the trees, animals, minerals etc and the imaginary order is woven into this reality very closely.</p> <p>The moment we are born society around us will start telling us stories about imagined order. Most of the people who believe in these stories think that their worth depends on their position in social hierarchy and what other people think about them. Most of our present day desires are created by romantic, nationalist, capitalist and humanist myths. It is very difficult to change an imagined order because it requires changing of collective imagination of billions of people. Harari is saying</p> <p><em>“Inorder to change an existing imagined order, we must first believe in an alternate imagined order”</em></p> <p>**Racism<br/> **After agriculture revolution with the help of myths and stories humans organised themselves in imagined orders. Racism was one such thing created as a result of this ordering. Harari underlines that biologically and logically there is negligible difference between people in different social orders. So racism can be the result of chance events supported by myths.</p> <blockquote> <p>Culture tends to argue that it forbids only that which is unnatural. But from a biological perspective, nothing is unnatural. Whatever is possible by definition also natural. A Truly unnatural behaviour, one that goes against the laws of nature, simply cannot exist, so it would need no prohibition.</p> </blockquote> <h3 id="3-unification-of-humankind"><strong>3. Unification of Humankind</strong></h3> <p>Now if you look around humankind is a one big family above the globe. We communicate and work together for the progress of this big family. But after agriculture revolution it was not like that. Humans were spread across different continents, cultures and societies. So what brings them together. There are three things that united human beings</p> <p>**1. Money and Trade<br/> **Trade started with barter system. But it had its own flaws. When money came into picture it became a universal medium of exchange also it became the most efficient system of mutual trust ever devised.</p> <p><strong>2. Imperialism</strong><br/> Rise and fall of empires played a large role in uniting human kind. Throughout the history empires ruled over large geographical areas and united them under common myths. In this process they did a lot of bloodshed. We can fill pages with good things and bad things about imperialism but the end result is that this process helped in uniting humankind.</p> <p><strong>3. Religion</strong><br/> Harari is defining religion as a <strong>system of human norms and values that is founded on a belief in a superhuman order.</strong> One theory about the origin of gods is that gods gained importance because they offered a solution to the problem of communication with plants and animals. This further led to the formation of polytheistic religions. Originated from polytheistic religions monotheists religions believed only in one supreme power. Over time it went through a lot of transformation.</p> <blockquote> <p>“The monotheists religions expelled the gods through the front door with a lot of fanfare, only to take them back in through the side window.”</p> </blockquote> <p>Religion is often considered as the source of discrimination and disunion but it was one of the three important things that united human beings in a larger scale.</p> <h3 id="4-scientific-revolution"><strong>4. Scientific Revolution</strong></h3> <p>In this section Harari talks about the scientific revolution which begins 500 years ago. Scientific revolution triggered industrial revolution and that triggered information revolution and currently the biotechnological revolution. He is concluding this section with the mention of replacing natural selection with intelligent design and suspect that biological revolution might saw seeds for the end of Sapiens.</p> <p>Overall I enjoyed reading this book. It really connected many dots in the evolution of human beings. I would  recommend this book to anybody who is interested in the story of sapiens.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Books"/><category term="Books"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Once in a while you will read a book and it will bring a radical shift in your perspective. Sapiens is a book like that. This books tells us how an animal born with no significance grown to become god like. Dr. Yuval Noah Harari did a great job writing the entire human history in just 400 pages. His simple writing style and presentation with illustrations explains each and every concept perspicaciously.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My year 2016 in Books</title><link href="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2016/my-year-2016-in-books/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My year 2016 in Books"/><published>2016-12-31T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-31T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2016/my-year-2016-in-books</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nikhilvishnu.github.io/blog/2016/my-year-2016-in-books/"><![CDATA[<p>I have always loved and enjoyed reading. Until recently I considered myself a casual reader. However as I look back on my journey of reading; I realize 2016 has been a huge turnaround and has turned me into a rather voracious reader.</p> <p>I got opportunities to closely interact with an amazing set of people who introduced me to different genre of books. Some inspired me with their thoughtful, wise and interesting thoughts of books that they have read. Some went a step ahead and gifted me some wonderful books. So here I am as dusk falls on 2016; to ring a wonderful 2017; with 30+ books in my reading repertoire.</p> <ol> <li>Zero to One: Notes on Startups, or How to Build the Future<br/> by Peter Thiel</li> <li>To Kill a Mockingbird (To Kill a Mockingbird #1)<br/> by Harper Lee</li> <li>മനുഷ്യന് ഒരു ആമുഖം | Manushyanu Oru Aamugham<br/> by Subhash Chandran</li> <li>ഫ്രാൻസിസ് ഇട്ടിക്കോര | Francis Itty Cora<br/> by T.D. Ramakrishnan</li> <li>What I Talk About When I Talk About Running<br/> by Haruki Murakami</li> <li>Philosophy: Who Needs It<br/> by Ayn Rand</li> <li>Heroes of History<br/> by Will Durant</li> <li>Sophie’s World<br/> by Jostein Gaarder</li> <li>My Name is Red<br/> by Orhan Pamuk</li> <li>Kafka on the Shore<br/> by Haruki Murakami</li> <li>The Republic<br/> by Plato</li> <li>The Metamorphosis<br/> by Franz Kafka</li> <li>A Ne Earth: Awakening to Your Life’s Purpose<br/> by Eckhart Tolle</li> <li>Go Set a Watchman (To Kill A Mockingbird #2)<br/> by Harper Lee</li> <li>The Road<br/> by Cormac McCarthy</li> <li>Meditations<br/> by Marcus Aurelius</li> <li>ഹിഗ്വിറ്റ | Higuita<br/> by ‌‌N.S. Madhavan</li> <li>Five Past Midnight in Bhopal: The Epic Story of the World’s Deadliest Industrial Disaster<br/> by Dominique Lapierre</li> <li>Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance: An Inquiry Into Values<br/> by Robert M. Pirsig</li> <li>Animal Farm<br/> by George Orwell</li> <li>Sidhartha<br/> by Hermann Hesse</li> <li>Interpreter of Maladies<br/> by Jhumpa Lahiri</li> <li>Walden<br/> by Henry David Thoreau</li> <li>Predictably Irrational: The Hidden Forces That Shape Our Decisions<br/> by Dan Ariely</li> <li>Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind<br/> by Yuval Noah Harari</li> <li>I Am Malala: The Story of the Girl Who Stood Up for Education and Was Shot by the Taliban<br/> by Malala Yousafzai</li> <li>Pride and Prejudice<br/> by Jane Austen</li> <li>Homo Deus: A Brief History of Tomorrow<br/> by Yuval Noah Harari</li> <li>1984<br/> by George Orwell</li> <li>കഥകള്‍ | Kadhakal<br/> by Unni R.</li> <li>The Little Prince<br/> by Antoine de Saint-Exupéry</li> <li>James Herriot’s Dog Stories<br/> by James Herriot</li> <li>How to Win Friends and Influence People<br/> by Dale Carnegie</li> <li>എന്‍മകജെ | Enmakaje<br/> by Ambikasuthan Mangad</li> </ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Books"/><category term="Books"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have always loved and enjoyed reading. Until recently I considered myself a casual reader. However as I look back on my journey of reading; I realize 2016 has been a huge turnaround and has turned me into a rather voracious reader.]]></summary></entry></feed>